RG 079:018, Office of Indian Affairs
Connecticut State Library
Office of Indian Affairs' records
1836-1995
bulk 1976-1995
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Office of Indian Affairs
10.5 cubic feet
The Office of Indian Affairs works with the Connecticut Indian Affairs Council (CIAC) and coordinates activities relating to the state's American Indian population and state Indian reservations. The CIAC's responsibility is to advise the Dept. of Environmental Protection Commissioner on matters relating to Connecticut's five tribes.
RG079_018
Multiple
Historical Note
The Office of Indian Affairs works with the Connecticut Indian Affairs Council (CIAC) and coordinates activities relating to the state's American Indian population and state Indian reservations. The CIAC's responsibility is to advise the Dept. of Environmental Protection Commissioner on matters relating to Connecticut's five tribes.1
Endnotes
1Leslie Carothers report, 1989, RG 079:001, Ennvironmental Protection, Commissioner Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., Accession 2005-009, Organizational Evaluation, Box 6, Folder "Historic Org Charts".
Scope and Content
Includes Legislative Task Force on Indian Affairs, 1988-1994; Native American Heritage Advisory Council, 1982-1995; Indian Affairs Coordinator, Office of Indian Affairs (DEP), 1956-1991; Golden Hill Paugussett Tribe, 1836-1995; Pequot Tribes, 1931-1978; Series 6. Miscellaneous Documents, 1925-1977.
Arrangement
Series 1. Legislative Task Force on Indian Affairs, 1988-1994, Accession: 1996-015 and 1996-026.
Series 2. Native American Heritage Advisory Council, 1982-1995, Accession: 1996-015
Series 3. Indian Affairs Coordinator, Office of Indian Affairs (DEP), 1956-1991, Accession: 1996-015
Series 4. Golden Hill Paugussett Tribe, 1836-1995, Accession: 1996-015
Series 5. Pequot Tribes, 1931-1978, Accession: 1996-015
Series 6. Miscellaneous Documents, 1925-1977, Accession: 1996-015
Addenda
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Office of Indian Affairs; Connecticut. Task Force on Indian Affairs
Subjects:
Connecticut. Office of Indian Affairs -- Records and correspondence; Indians of North America -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Legislative Task Force on Indian Affairs, 1981-1994
  - 1996-015
    - Records, 1988-1994
      - Meeting minutes, agendas, background material (Box 1)
      - Correspondence: Eastern Pequot, Golden Hill Paugussett, Mohegan, Schaghticoke Tribes and miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Subject Files (Box 1)
        - Connecticut Indian Affairs Council (CIAC) (Box 1)
        - Formation of Task Force, Objectives and Membership (Box 1)
        - Indian Customs, Religion and Artifacts (Box 1)
        - Land Issues (Box 1)
        - Legal Matters (laws and legislation) (Box 2)
        - Meskill to O'Neill (Essay on Indian Policy) (Box 2)
        - Reports, recommendations and summaries (Box 2)
        - Sovereignty / jurisdiction (Box 2)
  - 1996-026
    - Records, 1981-1990; 1 envelope (Box Item 1)
      Includes correspondence, meeting notices, attendance sheets, minutes, reports, legislative material, and background material.
- Series 2. Native American Heritage Advisory Council, 1982-1995; 1996-015
  - Meeting minutes, agendas, notices (Box 3)
    - 1989 November - 1990 June (Box 3)
    - 1990 June - December (Box 3)
    - 1991 January - June (Box 3)
    - 1991 July - December (Box 3)
    - 1992 January - December (Box 3)
    - 1993 January - 1994 December (Box 3)
  - Background material from Edward Sarabia (Box 3)
  - Administrative Matters (Box 3)
    - Freedom of Information Act (Jerry Walden) (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Membership (Box 3)
  - Land suits, law enforcement, federal recognition (Box 4)
  - Legal matters (Box 4)
    - Comments on proposed acts/regulations (Box 4)
    - Legislative acts (Box 4)
  - Legislative Task Force on Indian Affairs (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Museums Archaeological Collections (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 4)
  - Other State Agencies (Box 4)
- Series 3. Indian Affairs Coordinator, Office of Indian Affairs (DEP), 1956-1991; 1996-015
  - Florence Barrell, Estate Administrator (Box 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1956-1966 (Box 5)
  - Edward Sarabia and other staff (Box 5)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1980-1991 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1983 (Box 5)
      - 1984 February - December (Box 5)
      - 1985 January - August (Box 5)
      - 1985 September - 1987 February (Box 6)
      - 1987 March - 1988 June (Box 7)
      - 1988 July - 1989 June (Box 8)
      - 1989 July - December (Box 9)
      - 1990 January - December, 1991 May (Box 10)
- Series 4. Golden Hill Paugussett Tribe, 1836-1995; 1996-015
  Reports, correspondence, newspaper clippings, maps, legislation, and genealogical data. Some materials are not dated.
  Some of these documents are photocopies.
  - 1836-1981, undated (Box 11)
  - 1982-1993 September (Box 12)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 13)
    Includes genealogies.
- Series 5. Pequot Tribes, 1931-1978; 1996-015
  Correspondence and genealogical data.
  - Eastern Pequot Tribe
    - A - C (Box 14)
    - E - Seb (Box 15)
    - Seb - Spe (Box 16)
    - Spe - W (Box 17)
  - Western Pequot Tribe (Box 17)
    - B - W (Box 17)
- Series 6. Miscellaneous Documents, 1925-1977; 1996-015
  - Indian history
    - Connecticut State Parks and Forest Commission (Box 18)
      - Meeting minutes, 1925-1939 (Box 18)
      - Excerpts from annual reports, 1930-1942 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence, 1926-1941, undated (Box 18)
    - Map of land and R.J. Huard, Killingly, 1977 October (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1957 (Box 18)
    - Notebook of J.R. Williams (Box 18)
    - Transcript of legislative hearing regarding H.B. 347, 1939 February 28 (Box 18)
    - Welfare Department (Box 18)
      - Correspondence and papers, 1945-1973 (Box 18)
      - Tribal funds (Box 18)
        - Annual reports, 1941-1973 (Box 18)
        - Correspondence, 1941-1977 (Box 19)
      - Appropriations and Expenditures (Box 19)
        - Appropriation summaries, 1941-1967 (Box 19)
        - Appropriation summaries - Tribal funds for Schaghticoke, Western and Eastern Pequot Tribes (Box 19)
        - Expenditure summaries for Western and Eastern Pequot, Schaghticoke, Golden Hill Tribes (Box 19)
        - Tribal funds miscellaneous (Box 19)
- Addenda
  - 2007-026
    - Records, 1956-1994 (Box 1)
      These records are photocopies of material listed in Series 1, entire; Series 2, Meeting minutes and administrative matters; Series 3, Florence Barrell correspondence. They were copied by the Historical Research Department of the Mashantucket Pequot Museum & Research Center as part of their Native American Records Preservation Project.
  - 2008-019
    - "American Indian Census - Connecticut, Simmary Tables", undated (Box Shared box)
    - "American Indians in Connecticut, A Report of a Statewide Census", 1977 (Box Shared box)